With your current physical condition, Madam,
even if you use our sect's spiritual medicine,
I am afraid you won't fully recover.
I can only blame myself
for arriving too late.
Why do you say that, Master?
If anyone is to blame,
it is my ill fate.
I lacked the fortune
to meet you earlier, Master.
However,
hearing you mention the spiritual medicine,
I also know a bit about pharmacology.
I wonder
if you could let me see one.
Of course.
Madam Zhao,
please have a look.
Though this medicine is miraculous,
it uses the method of
fighting poison with poison.
You must take it once a day,
and
never stop for more than three days.
Otherwise,
it will turn into a lethal poison.
Also, first-time users
will experience drowsiness.
It is best you just look at it, Madam Zhao.
You must never
take it casually.
Thank you for the reminder, Master.
Cinnabar,
ginseng,
and eucommia.
Also raw aconite and five-poison root.
Both raw aconite and five-poison root are extremely toxic drugs.
As expected,
it's a good way to fight poison with poison.
It works.
It really works.
Zhu'er.
Uncle,
why aren't you asleep yet?
Sister-in-law,
do you want to go home too?
We'll go home tomorrow.
My lords,
please let us go home.
I, Meng Qian, am just a street idler.
I have a sister-in-law and a sister to take care of at home.
My family are all ordinary commoners.
Such a big matter
is definitely not something I can participate in.
Whether it's assassinating the Emperor or saving him,
I just want to live my own life.
Taoist Priest,
I also hope
you can give my sister the elixir.
Lord Duzhi,
can you restore my sister-in-law and sister's freedom?
Tonight,
I saw an idler from Sangjia Wazi
die right in front of me.
I...
My sister is already weak and ill,
and she is even more innocent.
So your big plan
is really beyond my ability.
Young Brother Meng,
it's not beyond your ability.
On the contrary,
the key to the success or failure of this matter
might
be you.
We have analyzed the current situation.
If we want to climb Fanlou on the night of the Lantern Festival,
it will be harder than climbing to heaven.
The best way
is to go through the underground canal and river,
and pass through Wuyou City.
And for this method,
only you can do it.
Because
you know the geographical environment here
and can lead the way for us.
Taoist Priest,
My lords,
good people.
I, Meng Qian, am afraid of death.
If I die, what will happen to my sister?
Please let me go,
let my family of three go.
Young Brother Meng,
I am untalented,
but I want to play a song on the qin for you.
I wonder
if you'd do me the honor.
Lady Zhao's zither music
truly soothes the mind.
Hero Meng,
you flatter me.
I wouldn't dare call myself a hero.
Lady Zhao, please just call me Meng.
In my heart,
anyone who can protect
their family
is the truest hero.
Protecting my family
is my only wish.
Protecting one's family
is also the wish of everyone in the world.
Brother Meng.
Have you ever thought about it?
With the Lantern Festival approaching,
if the Emperor is assassinated,
various factions will rise up,
and the world will fall into chaos.
How many innocent people
will be displaced
and lose their loved ones?